Harmony Morse

Software Engineer | Full Stack | iOS | DevOps

Kenmore, WA | 425-470-3375 | harmonythedev@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

As an enthusiastic autistic software engineer, I've refined my skills in web development, iOS development, and DevOps through a bootcamp and mentor-guided learning. I'm dedicated to using this combination of experiences and technical expertise to contribute to a team focused on creating accessible, inclusive technology that serves as a tool for social good and connects and empowers people across the globe.

SKILLS

Specialties: iOS, Full-Stack, DevOps, Git, Mobile Design, Responsive Design, MVC, OOP

Languages: Swift, zsh, JSON, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML, EJS, Python, SQL **Libraries and Frameworks:** UIKit, React, Node.js, Axios, Django, AJAX, Express.js

Databases and other: RESTful APIs, MongoDB, SQL, noSQL, PostgreSQL, DOM, Virtual Machines, Data Structures

Tools: Xcode, VS Code, Auto Layout, GitHub, CLI, Heroku, Figma

Interpersonal skills: Analytical, Detail Oriented, Articulative, Eager and Quick Learner, Adaptable

EXPERIENCE

Indio, iOS Developer

Remote, 1/2024 - Present

- Collaborates with a team of developers to maintain and improve iOS app
- Debugs industry-sized application using Xcode debugger
- Communicates with backend team to refactor API endpoints for smoother routing

General Assembly, Software Engineering Fellow

Remote, 11/2023 - 2/2024

- Completed 480+ hours of expert-led training on in-demand technologies
- Expanded knowledge in JavaScript, Python, React, Django, Node.js, and more
- Developed and deployed 4 major web products

PROJECTS

Insight - GitHub | Live Site - Django | Python | PostgreSQL - 1/16/24

A mobile-centric web app designed to allow users to track, analyze, and take control of their emotional lives

- Collaborated with team members to deploy in a four-day development sprint
- Designed a custom user model for secure authentication and authorization
- Created wireframes using Figma for the application's user experience
- Developed an effective and predictable prompt for use in the ChatGPT integration

Novel Navigator - GitHub - MongoDB | Express | Node.is | Google OAuth - 12/19/23

A dynamic full-stack application for tracking characters within books, movies, or projects

- Enhanced user experience by designing a navigable and aesthetic interface
- Integrated client-side interfaces seamlessly with robust server-side components
- Utilized Google's API with OAuth 2.0 for streamlined authentication and authorization to bolster user security

Tile Tap - GitHub | Live Site - JavaScript | HTML | CSS - 11/28/24

An adaptive front-end browser game inspired by the classic "Whack-a-Mole" arcade game

- Built responsive application utilizing JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Coded game logic using JavaScript to create a reactive game for mobile and desktop users
- Developed hover effects on buttons using CSS to render a responsive and appealing user experience

Relative Path 6 - Cycle 5 | Cycle 6 - Shell | Multipass | Nginx - 9/22/23-12/13/23

Scripts to host a virtual machine, launch a web server on the VM, and destroy the VM when finished

- Collaborated with other students to create cross-platform scripts
- Tested Darwin scripts to ensure functionality and identify potential issues

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Software Engineering

12 week full-time full-stack software engineering program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Relative Path, DevOps

Remote, Continuous, Started: 07/2023

125+ hours of daily expert-led instruction on crucial DevOps topics including bash, Git, automation, infrastructure as code, CI/CD pipelines, virtual machines, and cloud deployment.

Inglemoor High School, Diploma

Kenmore, WA, 09/2021-06/2023

Remote, Certificate: 02/2024

Graduated with a 3.9 GPA and Seal of Biliteracy in ASL; and completed two years of Running Start (College in the High School).